

Romel Niño O. Paano

Purok II, Plaridel Street, Baybayon, Looc, Mandaue City 09158237614/09989460098

rpaano02@gmail

Skype: rpaano02@gmail

Personal Profile

Age: 24 years old Date of Birth: January 15, 1998

Place of Birth: Bislig City Surigao Del Sur

Sex: Male Civil Status: Married

Religion: Apostolic Christian

Career Goal

My goal is to demonstrate more willingness to learn how to use cross-platform programming languages to build stand-alone applications, learning new techniques and improving my skills as a developer and becoming a software development team leader in the future.

Work Experience

Technical Specialist - Software Engineer II Alliance Software Incorporated March-2022— Present

- Working on projects like JFC.
- Improve rest api for the existing system.
- Assist creating the database structure.
- Develop RESTful API using VUE.js, PHP, SQL, Laravel, Drupal

Key Achievements: Learn unfamiliar technologies.

Junior Software Developer Yoshii Software Solutions Philippines September-2021 – February 2022

- Working as a full-time Junior Software Developer.
- Develop rest api for the existing system
- Assist creating the database structure.
- Restructure the old system, add and improve the functionalities.
- Develop RESTful API

Key Achievements: Improve existing systems that were previously slow and unresponsive.

Junior Backend Developer Next65 Solutions Inc. November-2019 – July-2021

- Working as a full-time Junior Backend Developer.
- Develop affiliate(networking) projects for clients.
- Communicate with the client's designer.
- Assist creating the database structure.
- Restructure the old system, add and improve the functionalities.
- Develop RESTful API

Key Achievements: Make a project without experiencing N+1 problems. Able to learn new programming techniques and skills from workmates or tutorials.

IT Staff

Sacred Heart School – Hijas de Jesus Jun-2019 – Nov-2019

- Assist in maintaining the school website.
- In-charge of the school website.
- Maintain, set-up and fix all computers of the school.

Key Achievements: Able to work under pressure and an unreliable system.

Educational Background

Xavier University – Ateneo de Cagayan Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Corrales Avenue, Cagayan de Oro City 2015 - 2019

Saint Vincent de Paul Diocesan College Andres Soriano Avenue, Bislig City 2003 - 2015

Special Skills

- Programming Languages PHP, JAVA, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.
- Framework (Laravel, Laminas, Vue, Bootstrap, jQuery, Angular)
- CMS (Drupal)
- Database scripting MySQL, MariaDB, Redis
- Vagrant, Docker, AWS

References

Princess Mae Buangjug Application Development Analyst Accenture Inc. 09958355438

Mark Saren Backend Developer Next65 Solutions 09395931016

Sr. Rachel Bade F.L. School Treasurer Sacred Heart School -Hijas de Jesus 09297064863